## **LUCY JONES**

## **CURRICULUM VITAE**

📞 07919098611 🖸 lucyjpjones@gmail.com 🍳 1 Ribblesdale Road, London, SW16 6SF 🛅 www.linkedin.com/in/lucy-jones-1304



## **PROFILE**

A self-motivated economics graduate currently working towards achieving a Diploma in Software Development.

With over 5 years of professional experience in merchandising and sales, I am a proven team player with success in working efficiently to solve problems and hit targets. I am excited to combine my strong analytical skills with excellent communication skills to embark on a new challenge in my career.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

### **FRONT END**

F HTML5

**3** CSS3

Js JavaScript

#### **BACK END**

Python3

## **TOOLS**

git (GitHub and GitPod)

## **EDUCATION**

## **Code Institute**

2020 - Present

Diploma in Software Development

## **Leeds Beckett University**

2011 - 2014

First Class Honors degree in Economics for Business (BA)

## **West Kirby Grammar School**

2004 - 2011

A Level: Product Design (A), Business and Economics (B), Mathematics (C)

AS Level: Geography (C)

10 GCSE's all A\* to C, including: Mathematics, English and

Science

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Debenhams, Senior Assistant Planner (Electricals-Personal Care)

November 2019- June 2020

- Managed my own department, Personal Care Electricals.
- Implemented department plans for forthcoming seasons through historical analysis and consideration of the business trading calendar and objectives.
- Proven success by over-achieving my sales plan last season by 104% and exceeding my target margin by 8%
- Lead the discussion around performance at supplier range reviews and liaised with the buyer to decide on the product range for the season.
- Reviewed and updated continuity line cards in order to action rebuys.
- Created adhoc reports to improve workflow efficiency and support the team in decision-making.
- Managed supplier funding to ensure we achieved our best product margins and took advantage of any marketing opportunities.
- Presented department figures in weekly trade meetings to divisional directors in the Merchandiser's absence.

## Foxtons, Letting Negotiator

May 2019-November 2019

 Actively sourced and managed my own client database while continuously building and maintaining strong rapport with over 100 applicants.

#### **PERSONAL SKILLS**

- Strong numerical and analytical skills
- Building and maintaining relationships
- Highly proficient in spreadsheets showing meticulous attention to detail
- Success in managing and developing others
- Exceptional organisational skills with proven ability to manage workload to meet deadlines and hit targets
- Strong negotiation skills applied within both retail and sales environment
- Commercial and customer awareness

## **ADDITIONAL SKILLS**

Advanced excel skills, confident using pivot tables and Vlookups

Full current clean driving license

## PERSONAL ACHIEVEMENTS & AWARDS

- Successfully completed 'Python for Everybody' through the University of Michigan on Coursera
- Code Institute '5 Day Coding Challenge'
- 'Learn Ruby' through CodeAcademy
- Diploma of professional Interior Design through the British College of Interior Design
- Awarded long lettings negotiator 'Hero of the Month' through Foxtons
- Completed the Liverpool half marathon raising over £1,000 for 'Made With Hope' charity
- Set up a 'virtual horse race day' through zoom raising over £400 for Pancreatic cancer
- Gold Duke of Edinburgh Award

- Handled incoming enquires from online, telephone and walk-ins, and provided support for front office with meet and greets and general administration.
- Used own initiative to conduct viewings tailored to the client's individual needs and followed up with feedback.
- Carried out rental inspections and took control of the entire referencing process and signing of contracts.
- Proven ability of meeting and exceeding personal targets by obtaining top performer recognition.

# Debenhams, Established Assistant Merchandiser (Women's Gifts, Seasonal & Gift Experiences)

September 2017- May 2019

- Managed my own departments and helped to deliver an annual sales revenue of over £25m.
- Monitored department performance and re-forecasted to ensure we were achieving our sales and profit targets, whilst highlighting any risks.
- Provided valuable coaching and training to allocators and new starters to help support their development.
- Supported the merchandiser with producing and maintaining planning sheets.
- Conducted detailed analysis to ensure appropriate product selection, quantities and phasing.
- Closely monitored in-season trading and identified opportunities for rebuys and markdown.
- Built strong relationships with suppliers in order to negotiate best payment terms, pricing and delivery times.
- Worked with finance to ensure any supplier payment queries were dealt with accordingly.
- Dealt with the set-up of recalls and product write-offs in stores.
- Department representative for improved and new stores, working closely with store planning to produce store plans and drive key decisions around product placement.
- Intake representative for home division attending regular meetings with logistics team.

## House of Fraser, Assistant Merchandiser (Private Label Men's Accessories)

May 2017 - September 2017

- Assisted the merchandiser in monthly re-forecasting.
- Analysed weekly reports and presented department figures to senior management in trade meetings.
- Created allocation plans and grade matrix for the season through analysis of store space and historical data.
- Managed a team of allocators to ensure an accurate and timely execution of intake and allocation.
- Reviewed and submitted markdown, completed promo-rolls and selected product for the promotional in-store events.
- Managed 'Best & Worst' to keep track of best/worst selling lines.
- Identified stock opportunities for transfers and recalls to help maximise sales potential.

### **PERSONAL INTERESTS**

- **Skiing**
- **◆** Yoga
- 3 Running
- Travelling

## **REFEREES**

Available upon request

- Attended store visits to develop commercial gain and maintain awareness of competition.
- Took ownership of running a competition between stores to help drive sales during an in-store event. As a result, sales averaged +15% vs. the previous year with the winning store taking an additional £70k on menswear.

## House of Fraser, Allocator (Branded Men's Accessories)

January 2015 - May 2017

- Created allocation plans and managed intake in line with phasing.
- Managed stock and replenishment by reviewing and updating stock profiles and grade tables.
- Inputted and updated promotional activity on the system (Mercatus).
- Monitored sales across all stores and actioned transfers and recalls to maintain optimum stock levels.
- Managed line cards to effectively monitor potential sales and assist the merchandiser in completing the monthly forecast.
- Prepared reports for Monday trade and provided sales and stock information for supplier meetings.
- First point of contact for distribution centre, suppliers and stores.
- Managed and led the monthly allocator meetings and provided training for new allocators entering the business.
- Participated in the buddy scheme and adopted the role of super LIMA user.